# Luke Powers

lukepow

## **PROFILE**

I'm a full-stack software engineer with multiple years of experience in both the Ruby and JavaScript ecosystems. Over the past 2 years, I've built a solid foundation in web engineering fundamentals that I'm eager to deploy on challenging projects that expand my current skill set and tech stack. Most recently I co-created Snowclone, an open-source BaaS with real-time capabilities.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Co-Creator and Software Engineer

2024 - present

Snowclone &

Snowclone is an open-source project that streamlines the process of creating and managing cloud infrastructure for database and APIs that support frontend applications and require real-time capabilities.

- Developed a containerized architecture for portable backends that provides APIs for schema migration, REST, and real-time notifications using a PostgreSQL database (Node.js, express, SSE,
- Designed a cloud deployment architecture that prioritizes scalability and cost-efficiency (ECS) Fargate, ELB, RDS)
- Leveraged Terraform to provision the 55 resources needed for each instance and to manage the state of projects deployed to AWS
- Built a CLI for managing the lifecycle of projects in AWS via terraform
- Authored a comprehensive technical case-study detailing the problem domain, system design, and engineering decisions
- Collaborated remotely with a team of four engineers using agile workflow

2022 - 2023**Software Engineer** 

Self-employed

Developed freelance and open-source applications including:

- Requestbin tool for collecting and debugging webhooks (DO Droplet, MongoDB, Nginx, React,
- Climbr A tool for posting and viewing rock climbing routes and areas (Ruby, Sinatra, PostgreSQL)

#### **Capital Markets Analyst**

2021 – 2022 | Richmond, VA

CapCenter

- Built and maintained dynamic pricing model and various reports to increase visibility of KPIs
- Achieved cost savings of >20% for the DM marketing channel by analyzing attribution and improving campaign targeting

# **SKILLS**

Languages

Libraries/Frameworks

JavaScript (ES6+), Ruby, Golang, Python, SQL

Node.js, Express, React, Sinatra

Other

AWS, Terraform, Digital Ocean, Heroku

Git/Github, Docker, Jest, HTTP/S, Websockets, SSE, OOP, REST APIs, Visual Studio

### **EDUCATION**

**Launch School** 2022 - 2023

Multi-year, mastery-based software engineering curriculum. Read more at launchschool.com/employers ∂

#### University of Richmond

2016 - 2020 | Richmond, VA

BS Business Administration, Finance Concentration